僕の人形を 止めて回ってる奴がいるんだ。 殺っちゃってくれる？ お任せください。
Fearsome monsters... Exotic creatures...
フン…　上等だ。
Vast riches... Hidden treasures...
戦車だろうが　戦闘機だろうが 全部　止めてやるよ。
Evil enclaves... Unexplored lands...
近いぞ。 ＯＫ。
Whoa! Wait! I'm awake! I'm awake...
道なりに来る。
Don't let me go!
いや…　直前で 俺の存在に気づくだろう。
However, you're down to twenty hours.
ポットクリンの利息時計が またカウントを始めるからな。
But now we have a 2-1 lead.
だが　このスピードなら…。
Now...
ポットクリンが 利息アップを告げる直前に
It's your turn!
奴を叩けるかもしれねえ
What do you want to bet on?
ナックルの能力「ハコワレ」は 敵についたポットクリンが
Trouble x With The x Gamble
１０秒ごとに敵に対して 利息アップを告知する しかし　敵がナックルから １００ｍ以上離れると
In the five-on-five battle
with the prisoners, Gon and his friends lead 2-1.
利息のカウントは　中断される
They're one win away from victory.
この時 次の利息アップまでの時間は
The fourth round is a series of wagers,
with time as the stakes.
ポットクリンの中で 記憶されており
What will they bet on next?
ナックルの半径１００ｍ以内に 敵が入った瞬間
Well, are you going to tell me
what the next bet will be?
直ちに　中断時間から再始動する
Or have you lost your nerve because
I've figured out your scheme?
およそ毎時１６０ｋｍから １８０ｋｍで向かって来る
Very well.
次の利息アップまでの時間が ３秒以上　残っていれば
H-Huh?
奴に気づかれず 攻撃できる可能性が高い
She's really cute...
あっ。
Then let's bet on whether
I'm a man or a woman.
どうした？
Huh? What's wrong? Is there a problem?
クソ！　どういうことだ!?
N-No.
直前で完全に 方向を変えやがった！
She's obviously a woman...
下だ!! ナックル！　無理だ　間に合わん。
Or could she be a tranny?
相手は　チーターの脚力を 持ってるんだ。
No, she's gotta be a woman.
奴は　「絶」に対応できないはずだ。 なぜ　待ち伏せがバレた？ まさか！
That's fine, but how will you prove if I'm wrong? Oh, right...
わずかだが　風下
Until you're fully satisfied.
風は巻いてもいねえし 向きも同じ においじゃ　ねえ 上だ！
Seriously? Her body?
何だ？　ありゃ。
Leorio will bet she's a man.
テレパシー 怪しい２人組を 見つけました　どうします？
Uh-huh. Huh? Why? Okay, I've decided.
テレパシー ほっとけ。 テレパシー ２人組は ターゲットじゃねえだろ。
I bet ten hours that you're a man!
テレパシー 余計な仕事なんざ する必要ねえよ。
I knew it.
テレパシー ハッ。
Dirty old man...
テレパシー
Huh? But how did you know?
テレパシー ほう　あいつも こっちに来てたのか。 テレパシー 鉢合う前に　ヂートゥ様に 知らせたのですが
This way, even if I'm wrong,
and it turns out she's female, I'll still get to examine her body!
テレパシー 余計でしたか？
It's a win-win situation.
テレパシー ヂートゥは　どうした？ テレパシー
Actually, please be wrong... There you have it.
テレパシー 「レオル様によろしく」と 礼を言って。
I get it now.
テレパシー そうか　よくやった。
Okay! Reveal the answer!
いい貸しが　できたぜ。 [TEL] レオルです。
Too bad... I'm a woman.
[TEL]　ターゲットがルォントン市の 歩兵大隊と一戦交えてる。
R-Really?
[TEL]　ルォントン市で？
Would you like to check?
一地区に　とどまってる時間が 確実に長くなってるニャ。
A mistake I do not regret.
何しろ　こいつ　３０時間以上 ぶっ通しで動き回ってる。
Just watching hurts... He's gonna lose. Huh?
ディーゴは　すでに 敵の手中に落ちた！ このまま家に閉じこもってると 殺されるぞ！
The opponent has seen through
Leorio's strategy. He's been betting conservatively, to minimize damage from either outcome.
ウソつき！ 反逆者め！ クソ！ 確かに　ディーゴ自らテレビで 健在ぶりをアピールしてるんだ
A gambler who focuses on avoiding
a loss won't ever win.
断然こっちの分が悪い 扇動は諦めるしかない
I guess Leorio just doesn't
have what it takes.
とにかく人形と軍隊を 手当たり次第に潰す！
As expected.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
His approach to gambling
doesn't frighten me at all.
次は 北のほう行くか。
He'll never beat me that way.
やっぱりだ まだ誰かついて来てる！
What do you want to bet on? This is no time to celebrate.
誰だ！　用があるなら出て来い！
I only have ten hours left...
完全に気配が消えた
If he loses the next wager,
the overall score will be 2-2.
仲間が集まるまで 尾行する気かもしれない
And we will have fifty fewer hours
to escape this tower.
絶対に振り切ってやる！ 根比べなら負けるもんか！ よぉ。 よっ。
Leorio... I can't lose the next bet, but I can't think of anything
that'd be a surefire win...
いや　どうせ道中だしね。 王は　この先だろ？　ハギャ。
Oh, that's it! We can bet on whether I'm
a man or a woman.
レオルだろ？　知ってるよ。
No, that wouldn't work... Hey, old man...
知ってて　わざとか… 相変わらず性格悪いな。
You're thinking aloud.
フラッタの忠告のおかげで 助かったよ。
I know. Leorio!
今　戦うのは嫌だったんでね。
Huh? How about whether or not
you're still in your teens?
そいつは　よかった ところで　そりゃ何だ？
Come on, Gon! I don't look that old...
ん？　さぁ？
I'm clearly a teenager!
ハンターに やられちゃったんだけどさ。
T-Teenager?
どんなに走っても ついて来るんだ　参ったよ。
But he looks like an old man.
けど　別に今んとこ 何の変化もないんだけど。
Right! In that case, we'll use
rock-paper-scissors!
取ってやろうか？
A bet on who'll win a game
of rock-paper-scissors!
それ　取ってやろうか？
Sure. Rock-paper-scissors?
できるのか？ 多分な。
Why did he have to pick
such a difficult wager? Huh?
タダじゃないだろ？
Rock-paper-scissors is hard?
ヘヘヘ…　察しがよくて助かるぜ。 だと思った。
I happen to be quite confident in
my rock-paper-scissors skill.
今　護衛軍から 仕事を任されててな。 それを手伝ってほしい。 テレパシー レオル様。
Just recently, I won a gourmet vacation
in a tournament in the shopping district.
テレパシー ターゲットを発見！ テレパシー ルォントン市の北東 国道沿いの山林を北上中です。
Let's see, then. I'll put eighty hours on my victory. E-Eighty hours?
ネフェルピトー殿の勘が ズバリ的中だな。
Is something wrong? I'm free to bet as much as I want.
テレパシー 絶対　見逃すなよ。 テレパシー 部下　総動員で足止めしておけ。
W-Well, that's true.
テレパシー ハッ！ 人間を１匹　追ってるんだ 恐らくハンターだろう。
And if you lose, I can still only
take ten from you. Don't worry.
そいつを狩る手伝いか。
She doesn't need to bet eighty.
ハンターねぇ
Ten would suffice.
あいつら　ひと筋縄じゃ いかないからなぁ。
What if she loses?
もちろん それは　先に取ってやるよ。
Or is she that confident?
あぁ…。 シャウアプフ殿が直々に お前に合った力を 見繕ってくれて
As anticipated, he's starting to stress.
習得のコツを伝授してくださる。
He's so easy to read.
早ければ一日で　ものにできるぜ？ まっ　俺は覚えが悪くて
While rock-paper-scissors has simple rules, the game itself is quite complex.
使いこなすのに ３日ぐらいかかったが。 すげぇ　おいしい話だなぁ。 見返りは　王への忠誠か？
If you consider the game
from a probability standpoint, there's only a one-third chance of losing.
「はい　はい」言ってりゃ いいわけだ。
However, if your opponent can predict
your reasoning and control your reactions, defeat becomes much more likely.
ヘヘヘ… お前は　ホントに察しがいい。
In other words, simple-minded Leorio
了解なら　一度　城へ戻って
will be at a disadvantage.
力をマスターしてから 俺に連絡をくれりゃいい。
I see.
それまでに獲物の力は 部下に探らせておくからよ。
All right! I've made my decision.
まっ　借りができたし　仕方ないか。
What?
それにしても 相変わらず　お前
It's obvious what you'll use.
おいしいとこだけ　持ってくなぁ。
I can read minds.
ヘヘヘ…　当然だろ。
Liar!
これでも　元は百獣の王だ。
Your bluffing won't scare me!
返り咲く気満々に 見えっけどねぇ
You'll believe me soon enough.
チッ… 完全に俺をマークしてるな
As planned, he's losing his
cool over a blatant lie.
あの距離じゃ ヨーヨーも全く届かない
She can read minds?
まくか　倒すかしないと 後々ヤバい
She's lying. She must be lying... But what if she's telling the truth?
あそこ！　ジャングルだ
Leorio will use rock. Huh?
ん？
Let's do this!
幾重にも葉が重なって
Rock... Paper...
上空からは 地上が全く見えないはず
Scissors!
低空で追って来たら ヨーヨーで迎撃できる！
You were right. Good guess.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
Nervous people unconsciously avoid any action that involves opening up. In other words, by making
Leorio uncomfortable, she ensures
来ない…　まいたか？
that he's less likely to use paper.
でも　俺を見失ったら 周囲を捜しに来るはず
So if she sticks with rock, she's guaranteed a win or draw.
クソ！ こっちは時間が惜しいんだ！ 来るなら早く来やがれ！
As I was explaining, rock-paper-scissors
is actually a mind game.
ハハハ…　どこに隠れようが 俺には見えるのさ
Now I see. Hold on.
テレパシー 行け！　レオル陸軍 見事　獲物を捕らえてみせろ！
Since we both used rock, wasn't that a draw? What of it? A-ha!
来た！　けど逆方向！ しかも　地上から!?
So you were lying about being
able to read my mind! If you really could, you'd have won. Right?
ハハハ…。
I deliberately gave you that tie. Quit lying!
あっ！
Did you forget?
おっ!?
We're trying to stall you here.
両腕を破壊！ 単独の接近戦では 勝ち目がねえ！
If I chose to, I could force an
indefinite series of draws...
テレパシー 奴は　どこだ！ テレパシー 隊長！　上です！
But that wouldn't be any fun.
キェ！ フン！ オリャ！
So I'll end this with the next turn. Well? What will you use next?
フン！
Think hard. Come on.
おっ！
Damn!
ぐっ…。 ぐわ！ テレパシー 殺られ…
Worry. Fret. Worrying. Fretting. When someone loses confidence,
they crave reassurance.
２匹　仕留め損なった 樹上での複数攻撃ですら 全く歯が立たない！
That makes him more likely to
either use the same hand, or, in an effort to regain his confidence, to use a stronger one than
in the previous round. Meaning
テレパシー 逃がすかよ！
that she wants Leorio to choose
either rock or paper.
てめぇが頭だろ！
Yes.
先に　デリートだ！
If she uses paper, she's certain not to lose. Then Leorio just needs to stay a step ahead!
フフフ… ヒャッハッハッハ！
Well, if he could calm down,
that might work. Leorio!
どよ！　俺の一発はよぉ！
What is it? Hey, you'll win if you go with scissors next!
あの野郎　俺に
Then she'll just use rock.
屁ぇかましやがった！
No, she'll go a step further
and choose paper.
いや　それよりも…
Wait, then she'll take another
step and use scissors...
完全に気配を断って 死角から攻めたにもかかわらず
No, no, then she'll take
another step and use rock...
完璧なタイミングで 反撃された
Man, I have no idea what to think!
遠隔で指示した奴が いたに違いねえ
Here we go! Here... comes the...
あいつだ！
draw!
特殊な力で　こっちの位置を 把握できるのかもしれない ならば…
I win!
電撃は　もちろん　ヨーヨーも できれば奴らに知られたくない
Rock-paper-scissors really is complicated. Now the score is 2-2.
理想は　奴らをまいて 潜伏し直すことだけど かなり無理くさい 全員　素手で倒すしか…
Worse yet, we have to give up
the fifty hours he lost.
銃!? いや　何か　ついてる　顔に！
Sorry. I was pretty confident in my
rock-paper-scissors ability.
ノミ!?
Well, I can't argue with you on this one.
痛っ　クソ！
Say, how much time do
they have left now?
どこから撃ってやがる！
Fifty-nine hours, forty-five minutes.
テレパシー エリアＴＨ８８ テレパシー Ｘ１５　Ｙ１２　Ｚ２
Which means they actually have fewer
than ten hours left.
テレパシー ポイント　Ｘ９　Ｙ３　Ｚ１。
It doesn't matter how much time they have.
テレパシー ＯＫ。
Because my opponent will die.
俺のフリーダムからは オ　イェイ うっ！
Hunter Vocabulary
クソ！
Rock-Paper-Scissors
こめかみの血が止まらない
It's finally time for the last round.
ただ　デカいだけの ノミじゃねえな!?
Guess I'm off.
テレパシー
What? Killua? What's that supposed to mean?
テレパシー ポイントＹ５　Ｘ３　Ｚ１。
Damn it! I really needed
to win my round... Gon... This guy is totally pissing me off!
ＯＫ。
Now, now.
ぐっ！
Depending on the opponent,
we still have a chance!
明らかに狙撃での ダメージが目的じゃ　ない
That little kid is their last member. Never thought I'd see him
fall prey to that monster.
むしろ　その後
Poor thing. He's still so young.
出血による 体力の消耗が狙いか！
I didn't want to use him.
フンフフフン
However, the Hunter Exam has no mercy.
オイラのノミは 特別製だぜ
If he dies here, that's fate. I'm removing his handcuffs.
「鬼に金棒」さ
You guys are getting too scared...
オ　イェイ
Idiot, stop!
おぉ！　もうよけるか。 猿軍団じゃ 手に負えないのも当然だ。
Is he really that terrifying? Isn't it all just ancient history?
私の「スーパーアイ」は サテライトンボの目を通し
Johness the Dissector.
あらゆる角度から ターゲットを観察できる！
The worst mass murderer in Zaban's history.
どんな能力だろうが 見逃さない
He chose his victims randomly.
さぁ　何かしてみな！
It was a famous case... 146 people, young and old, men and women,
met with brutal deaths by his hand.
キルアは「円」を使えない 全身を纏うオーラを 大きく広げ
He murdered all of them
with his bare hands. He was known for his iron grip, the power in his fingers.
それを長時間　維持する技術が 決定的に苦手であった キルアは　それを自覚している
It's been so long since
I touched human flesh.
だから　最も得意な幅で オーラをとどめていた
You don't have to face that psychotic killer...
その幅　５７ｃｍ
There's always next year.
あまりに狭い
Hey, Killua...
つまり先刻　キルアは
Killua!
銃弾が５７ｃｍの領域に 踏み込んだ瞬間 絶望的といえる短い有余の中
Damn it, was he even listening to me?! We should let him go.
超人的な反射神経と 身体能力で反応し
He could have a plan.
弾道の角度を 正確に測るため！
How are we settling this contest? Contest?
ぐっ…　チッ！
I believe you're confused.
この先から撃って来た！
This will be a one-sided massacre.
ほほう あえて何もしないことで
I have no interest in the exam
or any offer of amnesty.
狙撃手の位置を確かめたか
I just want to hear you scream.
テレパシー ターゲットが高速で そっちに移動しているぞ！
Really? Okay. Then the loser is the one who dies.
ＯＫ！ 想定の範囲内だぜ
Yeah, that's right.
ノミが　かすっただけの所は 血が止まってる
I'll tear your body apart.
ここなら　３６０度 全て見渡せる！
Wh-What?
どうだ！ もう　隠れようがないぞ！
I'm so cold.
待て！ この砂漠は ハンパねえ広さだ
G-Give it back.
コミュニケーションの時間が 増えたと考えようぜ。
Okay. That's three wins, two losses.
まずは　自己紹介。
We pass, right?
俺の名前は　ジェイル… じゃ　ねえ　メレオロンだ。 女王が生きてた時は 師団長をやってた。
Yeah, you win. By the way, you must be
itching for some action, since you didn't get to do anything.
よろしくな？ お前さんの名前は？
Want to play with me?
何で俺をつけてたの？
I'll abstain.
逃げられちゃ困るからさ。
Oh, okay.
死なれると　もっと困るしな。
Who is he?
何しろ 大事なパートナーだからよ。
That's right. You guys don't know. Huh? Don't know what?
王に用があるんだろ？
Killua comes from an elite family of assassins.
違う！ えっ？ 危ない…
Eh? A-An elite family of assassins? I'm back.
何か魂胆があって 近づいて来たんだ
What?
これ以上は　喋れない マジ？　お前ら 王を倒しに来たんじゃねえのか？
Uh... Well, good work!
お前さんが　もう一人の少年と 一緒だった時から見てたぜ。 なるほど。 えっ!?
Across the bridge, you'll find a small room.
それで俺のほうがキルアより やりやすいと思ったんだな！
You must spend the fifty hours
you gambled away there.
うわ…　そうとるかよ。
Yeah! R-Right...
だろうな！　信じられねえよな。 分かる！
Gittarackur, applicant #301,
is the second to pass.
俺だって　逆の立場なら…。 ん？
Total time, twelve hours
and two minutes.
えっ!?
I figured you'd already
crossed the finish line.
あいつか！
All right!
罠だぜ
Good grief.
それでも　来るかい？
We have to spend fifty hours
in this room?
知るかよ　死ね。
Can you tell me how that
technique works? Technique?
迷いない覚悟！　やるな
The one you used to instantly
remove his heart. Oh, that wasn't even a technique.
あ！
I just ripped it out. Ripped it out?
地底湖！ 地獄を見たイカ？ ここがそうだぜ！
But to make it easier, I manipulated my body a bit. Y-Your nails...
テレパシー 血！ エサだ！ テレパシー エサだ！
Mass murderers are still only amateurs. I used to be a professional.
テレパシー ん？　これは…
But my old man would've done better.
テレパシー イカルゴ隊長の宿主…。 テレパシー ヤベっ！　食うの中止！
When he removes a heart, you won't
see even a drop of blood.
テレパシー したいけど…　あ　無理！
How reassuring.
テレパシー 血が俺達を呼ぶんだよ！
As long as he's on our side... Well, then.
てめぇ！
We have more than two whole days. What should we do, Killua?
よくも このイカルゴ様の大事な足を
First, we should search the room
ぶった切ってくれたなぁ！
for any kind of entertainment. Yeah!
水の中に引き込まれると 厄介だからな。 助かったぜ　吸盤。
Man, you kids don't have
a care in the world.
タコって言うな！
Gon's team of five has passed the trial,
with three wins and two losses.
キルアをつけ狙っていたのは
However, they must spend the fifty-hour
penalty in this small room.
人に寄生するタコのような キメラアント　イカルゴだった
They're running out of time.